# **Boyapati Ashok Kumar**

Power Bi Developer with 4.2 years of experience in Designing, Creating and Implementing BI solutions, Creating interactive visual reports using BI tools, Identifying key performance indicators (KPI) to help companies adjust and fulfill objectives.

#### **GET IN CONTACT**

Mobile: +91-9701844953

Email: boyapati.ashokkumar123@gmail.com

#### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Total Experience 5 Years 2 MonthsCurrent Location Bangalore/Bengaluru

• Date of Birth Feb 06, 1994

Gender Male

Marital Status Single / Unmarried

#### **SKILLS**

- · Microsoft Power Bi
- Power Bi
- Dax
- MS SQL Server
- Powerpivot
- Business Intelligence
- Data Visualization
- Data Modeling
- Dax Studio
- SSRS

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Power BI All
- · Dax Queries
- SQL

#### **LANGUAGES KNOWN**

- English
- Telugu

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Having around 4.2 years of experience as Power BI developer with 5 years overall IT experience Good experience in Power BI Desktop and Power BI Service, Advance Excel, SQL

Experience in connecting with multiple data sources like SQL Server, Oracle, Snowflake and Excel from Power BI to build complex Datasets. Extensively worked in Power View for Presenting the Data in Graphical Format using Different Visualizations in Power BI.

Experience in publishing the Reports to Power BI Service and setting up the necessary connections.

Implemented ROW LEVEL SECURITY (RLS) as part of security in Power BI.

Experience in MS Power BI concepts like Data Modeling, DAX Functions, creation of Power BI Charts & Graphs(Gauge, Slicers, Funnel, KPI, Matrix, and Custom Visualizations).

Designed and deployed reports with Drill Down and Drill Up menu options and parameterized views

Published/shared the reports by creating a content pack/sharing the .pbix file.

Experience in creating worksheets and Dashboards by using Excel as a data source. Generated Dashboards with Quick filters, Parameters, and sets to handle views more efficiently.

Created daily, weekly, monthly and quarterly reports based on the customer requirements.

Experience in sharing the Reports and Dashboards with End Users.

Hands-on Experience in writing SQL Queries as part of testing the Data.

Good data knowledge from SQL, AWS, Sales Force, Advance exce

#### **EDUCATION HISTORY**

### Graduation

Course B.Com( COMPUTERS )

College Sri Krishnadevaraya University (SKU)

Year of Passing 2014 Grade 62%

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Oct 2021 to Present

#### Senior Software Engineer at IBM

Good Experience on Power Query, Power pivot and DAX functions. Experience in Created charts like Lines, Pies, Bar, Scatter, Area, Tree map, Map, filled map, Single Card, Multi row card, Slicer etc. Importing Custom Visuals from Microsoft Power Bi gallery as per client request Experience in Working on DAX functions like Date and Time functions, Filter, Logical, and Text. Experience in Publish the Power bi report to power bi services. Design, development and support implementation of interactive visual Power bi dashboards and reports. Interact with business owners in client organization to understand current and future requirement and document functional and technical specifications. Working on MS SQL Server and written queries to pull the data. Created Databases, Tables, Views, Constrains, Index, Functions and Store procedure. Filter the given data by customer need. Good understanding of SQL concepts like Grouping, sub queries, Functions etc. Solid understanding of SQL Joins(Inner Joins, Left joins and Right Joins and Full Joins) Good Knowledge of DDL, DML and TCL . Good Experience in Creating, Modify and Manage tables, Views ,Functions and Store procedures. Create New login, Managing and sharing all the sql Server activities to Users. Having Experience on SSIS in creating simple packages. By using SSIS Tool is converting the one data source to other data base. Designed and developing SSIS packages using different transformations like Conditional Split, Multicast, Union-All, Merge, Merge Join and Derived Column. I have good experience in Shear point, Slack and Outlook

Oct 2020 to Sep 2021

## Senior Software Engineer at Happiest Minds Technol ogies

Good Experience on Power Query, Power pivot and DAX functions. Experience in Created charts like Lines, Pies, Bar, Scatter, Area, Tree map, Map, filled map, Single Card, Multi row card, Slicer etc. Importing Custom Visuals from Microsoft Power Bi gallery as per client request Experience in Working on DAX functions like Date and Time functions, Filter, Logical, and Text. Experience in Publish the Power bi report to power bi services. Design, development and support implementation of interactive visual Power bi dashboards and reports. Interact with business owners in client organization to understand current and future requirement and document functional and technical specifications. Working on MS SQL Server and written queries to pull the data. Created Databases, Tables, Views, Constrains, Index, Functions and Store procedure. Filter the given data by customer need. Good understanding of SQL concepts like Grouping, sub queries, Functions etc. Solid understanding of SQL Joins(Inner Joins, Left joins and Right Joins and Full Joins) Good Knowledge of DDL, DML and TCL. Good Experience in Creating, Modify and Manage tables, Views , Functions and Store procedures. Create New login, Managing and sharing all the sql Server activities to Users. Having Experience on SSIS in creating simple packages. By using SSIS Tool is converting the one data source to other data base. Designed and developing SSIS packages using different transformations like Conditional Split, Multicast, Union-All, Merge, Merge Join and Derived

Column. I have good experience in Shear point, MS teams and Outlook

Mar 2018 to Sep 2020

#### **Software Engineer at Tech Mahindra**

## **PROJECTS**

#### Amerisource Bergen (Trenton), 393 Days

AmerisourceBergen Corporation is an American drug wholesale company that was formed by the merger of Bergen Brunswig and Amerisource in 2001. They provide drug distribution and consulting related to medical business operations and patient services. They also distribute a line of brand name and generic pharmaceuticals, over-the-counter (OTC) health care products and home health care supplies and equipment to health care providers throughout the United States.

#### Henkel, 12 Months

Globally, Henkel operates with leading innovations, brands and technologies in three business areas: Adhesive Technologies, Beauty Care and Laundry & Home Care, while in India it operates in two business areas: Adhesive Technologies and Beauty Care. The company holds leading positions with its three business units in both industrial and consumer businesses thanks to strong brands, innovations and technologies. Henkel Adhesive Technologies is the global leader in the adhesives market? across all industry segments worldwide. Henkel looks back on more than 140 years of success.

#### **OPTIMS, 12 Months**

OPTIMS Hotel enables hotels to forecast their future business and optimize revenue by offering the right price, to the right customer at the right time. Yield Management gives you the tools to manage your rates and availability according to demand and in such a way that maximum contribution is reached. OPTIMUS Hotel works alongside your front office system to give up to date reports and recommendations. Thanks to the ongoing analysis and forecasting of data, OPTIMUS Hotel issues dynamic recommendations each and every day, such as: Prices to sell at Limiting room sales by price under and over booking limits Minimum or maximum length of stay Minimum selling price.